Mark Lam

1770 Dean Street Brooklyn, New York USA +1 661 478 9651

mark@markofthelam.com

markofthelam.com github.com/emceelamb

Mark Lam is a sculptor and media scholar turned developer. He has a background in visual design and has developed websites and digital design for e-commerce and independent business. Most recently he has been working towards a Master's degree at New York University where he researches media making with computer networking technology. His other interests include teaching programming, digital accessibility, and reading about media theory.

Areas of Interest

- Computer Networking for Expressive Media
- Interactive Physical-Digital Interfaces Development
- Real-time Tangible Data Visualization
- Empathetic Conceptual Development

Education

2020 Interactive Telecommunications

New York University, New York City

2015 Media Studies & Art Practice

University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley

2013 Graphic Design

College of the Canyons, Valencia

Previous Experience

2015-ongoing S1

Self-employed Freelance Developer NYC, HCMC, LA, Berkeley

- Design and develop websites for business ranging from personal artist websites to independent publishing houses
- Research and advise clients for web features including image api's to online payment procedure
- Scope timelines and specifications and work with clients to meet objectives

2018–2019 Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts Digital Accessibility Fellow

New York City

- · Audit internal and external digital media of a world-class performing arts institution for WCAG 2.1 compliance
- Create internal digital accessibility training material to promote access for a diverse LCPA customer base
- · Design and developed a fully compliant digital map of campus accessibility features to allow for increased physical access
- Created a captioning work process for a catalog of over 1000 hours of video content to bring media to digital compliance

2018–2020 New York University - ITP

Graduate Assistant - Web Accessibility Developer

New York City

- Developed and tested an internal help site for New York University's ITP program
- · Work directly with faculty and staff to scope information priorities for
- · Implemented WAI-ARIA features to meet WCAG 2.1 compliance and university wide accessibility iniative

2017–2018 Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology & Education

Visiting Lecturer - Introductory Programming, English

Ho Chi Minh City

- · Developed an introductory English/programming curriculum in the C language for non-native English students
- Designed supplemental workshops for specialized topics such as web design and portfolio building
- · Collaborated with student leaders to promote extracurricular English

Projects & Workshops

2020 **Automating Mindfully**, Technical Workshop *Unconference at ITP NYU*, New York City

- · Introduction to Bash scripting
- · Explore mindfulness and technology

2019 Network Operator, Performance

2019

NIME 2019, New York City

- · Explore computer networking technology as medium for musical expression
- · Live network programming

Lincoln Center Campus Accessibility Map, Digital Map

Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts, New York City

- Create an accessible digital map of the Lincoln Center Campus
- Extend Google Maps API to incorporate WAI-ARIA features